A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Office of the City Engineer, Records, 1809-1975
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Architectural drawings and plans, 1809-1975.
  - Port - Tracing of a Portion of the Map of / Richmond Dock and Vicinity / from / 1st St to Ship Locks / Made by F. B. Isaacs Engr. W. P., 10761-A-2, 1919, Dimensions: 14-1/2 x 20 in. - 37 x 51 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: India ink and yellow ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 49)
    Drawn By: Office of Director of Public Work / Richmond, Va. / A. M. Harris Asst. Engr.
  - Port - [Soundings in port area], 11217-D-1, 1921, Dimensions: 30 x 39 in. - 76 x 99 cm.; Scale: 1" = 144'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 51)
    Drawn By: Chas. E. Bolling / Consulting Engr.
  - Port - General Plan / For / Deep Water Terminal / And / Rail And Highway Connections, Y-5038, 1938, Dimensions: 24 x 69 in. - 61 x 196 cm.; Scale: 1" = 500'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 49)
    Drawn By: Richmond Va. / Department of Public Works / Bureau of Survey & Design
  - Port - Map of / James River / and / Deep River Terminal / Showing Rail & Highway Connections / & Property Ownership, Y-6045, 1941, Dimensions: 37-3/4 x 77 in. - 94 x 195 cm.; Scale: 1" = 500'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 10)
  - Port - [Elevations of jetties in the James River], 38-A-5, n.d., Dimensions: 9-1/2 x 15 in. - 24 x 38 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 49)
  - Port - Comparative Statement of James River Improvement 1896-1915 Inclusive [chart], 90-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 22 x 35 in. - 56 x 89 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 49)
  - Port - Plan for City Wharf Ash Street, 11-A-5, n.d., Dimensions: 15-1/2 x 40 in. - 38 x 101 cm.; Scale: 1/2" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 49)
  - Railroad - Richmond, Va. / Map showing Tracks of the / Richmond & Danville Railroad / from Draw Bridge to C. & O. Junction, 9-C-2, 1892, Dimensions: 26 x 52-1/4 in. - 66 x 133 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Blueprint with linen tape backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: Office of Chief Engineer / Richmond and Danville R.R. / Atlanta Ga.
  - Railroad - C & O / Ry / Proposed / Improvements / in / Richmond, Va., 20-B-4, 1896, Dimensions: 21 x 35-1/2 in. - 53 x 90 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints with ink notations; Sheets: 28 (Folder 54)
    Drawn By: Each sheet signed by chief engineer of railroad and Richmond City Engineer W. E. Cutshaw.
  - Railroad - Richmond Ry and Electric Co. / Main and 14th. Sts., 50-B-5, 1897, Dimensions: 22 x 22 in. - 56 x 56 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: [Approval signature of W.S. Cutshaw, Richmond City Engineer]
  - Railroad - [Richmond Railway and Electric Co. right-of-way survey], 46-49-B-5, 1897, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 4 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: Richmond Railway and Electric Co. / Richmond, Va.
  - Railroad - Richmond Ry and Electric Co. / Crossing Over R.F. & P. Railroad. at Main and Belvidere Sts., 51-B-5, 1897, Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 25-1/4 in. - 42 x 64 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - Section No. 250 [cross-section of steel rail], 57 & 58 B-5, 1898, Dimensions: 15 x 10-1/4 in. - 38 x 26 cm.; Scale: Full size; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: The Pennsylvania Steel Co. Steelton, Pa.
  - Railroad - No. 8 Frog, Bolted Pattern Sec. No. 217 Rail, 53-B-5, 1898, Dimensions: 11-3/4 x 22-1/2 in. - 30 x 57 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: [Approval signatures of railroad official and W.S. Cutshaw, Richmond City Engineer]
  - Railroad - The Pennsylvania Steel Co. - Double Tongue Switch for Steam Railroads in Streets, 53-B-5, 1898, Dimensions: 15-1/4 x 29-1/2 in. - 39 x 75 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - Richmond Ry and Electric Co. / Approved Plan of Special Work, 52-B-5, 1898, Dimensions: 19 x 33-1/2 in. - 48 x 85 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: [Approval signatures of railroad officials and Richmond City Engineer]
  - Railroad - General Map & Profile / of the / Richmond Petersburg & Carolina R. R. / through the / City of Richmond, Va., 56-C-1, 1899, Dimensions: 18 x 34 in. - 45 x 86 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 8 (Folder 54)
    Drawn By: [Richmond Petersburg & Carolina Railroad]
  - Railroad - Map & Profile / of S.R.R. on Cary St. between 18th & 24th Sts., 32-A-1, 1900, Dimensions: 10 x 37-1/2 in. - 26 x 95 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
  - Railroad - Approval Plan [plan of railroad track at intersection of Seventh and Clay streets], 57-B-5, 1900, Dimensions: 21 x 29 in. - 53 x 74 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: The Pennsylvania Steel Co. Steelton, Pa. [signature of approval by W.C. Cutshaw, City Engineer]
  - Railroad - Map Showing Location of Gates Across Turpin St. / on S.A.L.R.R., 35-A-1, 1901, Dimensions: 13-3/4 x 11-3/4 in. - 35 x 30 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
  - Railroad - [Plan of railroad tracks in area of Harrison and Marshall Streets], 52-A-1, 1902, Dimensions: 10-1/2 x 17 in. - 27 x 43 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink and orange ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: Calvin Whitely Jr. and City Engineer / W.E Cutshaw / W.D. Duke Genl. Manager R.F.& P.R.R. Co.
  - Railroad - The strips shaded to be conveyed by the C. & O. Ry. Co. / to the City of Richmond, for the extension of Tredegar Street., 10-A-5, 1902, Dimensions: 16-1/4 x 21 in. - 41 x 53 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: W.E. Cutshaw / City Engineer.
  - Railroad - This part shaded to be / conveyed by R.F. & P. Ry. Co. to the City of Richmond, 17-A-2, 1902, Dimensions: 19-1/4 x 13 in. - 49 x 33 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: W.E. Cutshaw / City Engineer
  - Railroad - Sketch showing Bridge and / Conveyor to be erected by the / Richmond Flour and Feed Co, 38-A-2, 1902, Dimensions: 13-1/2 x 24 n. - 35 x 61 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
  - Railroad - [Details of steel girder railroad trestle (title block missing)], 45-A-1, 1903, Dimensions: 23-3/4 x 35-1/2 in. - 60 x 90 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: [Southern Railway (?)]
  - Railroad - Steam-Street R. R. Crossing / Seven Inch Girder Construction, 46-A-1, 1903, Dimensions: 20-1/2 x 30 in. - 52 x 76 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint (heavily damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: The Pennsylvania Steel Co., Steelton, Pa.
  - Railroad - 200-Foot Radius Switch & Mate, 36-B-4, 1905, Dimensions: 15-1/2 x 21 in. - 39 x 53 cm.; Scale: 1" = 5'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 55)
    Drawn By: The Pennsylvania Steel Company / Frog & Switch Dept. - Steelton, Pa.
  - Railroad - R. F. & P. R. R. / Plan of Re-Arrangement of Tracks / Across Harrison St. at Freight Warehouse, 29-B-4, 1905, Dimensions: 14-1/2 x 19 in. - 37 x 48 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: [Approval signature by W. E. Cutshaw, City Engineer, and General Manager of railroad]
  - Railroad - Culvert / Made for Shockoe Creek and Map of / Proposed Improvements / Made for / Shops & Tracks, 29-C-3, 1906, Dimensions: 18 x 23-3/4 in. - 46 x 60 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: 2 attached blueprints; Sheets: 2 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: American Locomotive Company
  - Railroad - Ironbound Manard Construction, 36-B-4, 1906, Dimensions: 15-1/2 x 21 in. - 39 x 53 cm.; Scale: 1" = 5'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 55)
  - Railroad - R.F. & P. R. R. / Plan of Proposed Spur Track / to / City Coal Company, 19-A-5, 1906, Dimensions: 13-1/2 x 17-1/2 in. - 34 x 44 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: [Approval signatures of City Engineer and railroad representative]
  - Railroad - Richmond, VA. / Sketch Plan for Track to / Brown Warehouse on 17th St., 21-C-1, 1906, Dimensions: 24-1/4 x 26 in. - 61 x 66 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 55)
  - Railroad - Map / Showing Proposed Industrial / Track / Manchester, Va., 56-C-2, 1909, Dimensions: 30 x 71 in. - 76 x 181 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: Asst. Engineer's Office / Raleigh, N.C.
  - Railroad - Plan of Suggested Arrangement / for So. Ry. Tracks on So. Dock St. / in order to give Morrison M. and S. Co. a siding, 37-B-3, 1909, Dimensions: 17-1/2 x 35-1/2 in. - 44 x 90 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: 1 India ink and red ink on linen, 2 blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: P.P. Taliferro / Asst. City Engr.
  - Railroad - Seaboard Air Line Ry. / Proposed Trestle Filling and change of Trestle Bents on Main Line in 16th. St, [No file number], 1909, Dimensions: 14 x 16-3/4 in. - 35 x 42 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 55)
    Drawn By: Division Engineers Office Richmond, Va.
  - Railroad - City of Richmond Va. / Map of Fulton Flats / and / The Southern Ry Tracks / Showing Proposed Changes, 63-A-2, 1909, Dimensions: 16-3/4 x 55 in. - 43 x 140 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: Office of City Eng'r. / From Original Surveys. / by Fontaine Jones / Asst. Engineer
  - Railroad - Southern Railway / Richmond, Va. / Proposed Change and Connection of Wharf Street, 63-A-2, 1910, Dimensions: 11-3/4 x 31 in. - 30 x 79 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint with ink and pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: O. Parati, A.E.
  - Railroad - Southern Railway / Manchester - VA / Proposed extension of Standard / Oil Co's track for D.M. Lea & Son, 31-A-6, 1910, Dimensions: 8-1/2 x 12 in. - 22 x 31 cm.; Scale: 1" =100'; Media: Blueprint with red ink notations (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: Office of Engr. Maint. Of Way / Northern District, Greensboro, N.C.
  - Railroad - Southern Railway / Richmond, Va. / Masonry Plan of Stone Arch over Gilies Creek at Wharf Street, 63-A-2, 1910, Dimensions: 13-1/4 x 9-1/2 in. - 34 x 24 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: Office of E.M.W. / Northern District / Greensboro, N.C
  - Railroad - [Assorted details of railroad track in Broad Street], 29-A-6, 1910, Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 11 (Folder 55)
    Drawn By: The Pennsylvania Steel Company / Frog & Switch Department, Steelton, Pa.
  - Railroad - R.F.& P.R.R. / Plan showing property between storage yard / and Leigh Street, 10584-B-1, 1911, Dimensions: 19-1/2 x 37-1/2 in. - 49 x 95 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: Blueprint (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - Plan of Platform / for Southern Express Co. / Under C & O and S. A. L. Train Shed / Main Street Station, 55-B-4, 1912, Dimensions: 20-3/4 x 33-1/4 in. - 53 x 84 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
  - Railroad - Virginia Railway & Power Co. / Proposed Change of Turnout on 7th. St. / North Of Leigh to 7th. St. North of Clay, 43-A-5, 1912, Dimensions: 8 x 24 in. - 20 x 61 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: Approved Chas. E. Bolling / City Engineer
  - Railroad - Seaboard / Air Line Railway / Proposed Steel Span / Marshall St., Richmond, Va., 80-A-2, 1913, Dimensions: 16 x 35-1/2 in. - 41 x 90 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 55)
    Drawn By: Office Bridge Engineer, Portsmouth, Va.
  - Railroad - Southern Railway Co. / Richmond, Va. / New Freight House Facilities / Study Plan 'M', 44-C-3, 1913, Dimensions: 26-1/2 x 32-1/2 in. - 67 x 83 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: Blueprint with colored ink and pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: Office of / Chief Engr. M. W. & S. / Southern Railway / Washington, D.C.
  - Railroad - Southern Railway / Proposed Reinforced Concrete Bridge / Lester Street Richmond, 54-C1, 1913, Dimensions: 23-1/2 x 35-1/2 in. - 60 x 90 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints with pencil notations; Sheets: 7 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: Office of Chief Engineer, M.W. & S. Wash. D.C.
  - Railroad - Southern Railway / Proposed Reinforced Concrete / Highway / Bridge at / Seventh St. - South Richmond, Va., 10441-B-1, 1914, Dimensions: 24 x 36 in. - 61 x 91 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: Office of Chief Engineer M.W.& S. Washington, D.C.
  - Railroad - Right of Way and Track Map / Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac R.R. / James River Branch, 11202-B-2, 1916, Dimensions: 24-1/2 x 56 in. - 62 x 142 cm.; Scale: 1" = 200'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 3 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: [R.F. & P. R.R.]
  - Railroad - Sketch Showing / Property to be Acquired from Mrs. Grace Smithdeal, 11246-A-2, 1917, Dimensions: 9 x 25 in. - 23 x 64 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Pencil and yellow pencil on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: Southern Railway System
  - Railroad - Drawing showing location of proposed railroad track across Second Street, 18-A-3, 1917, Dimensions: 24 x 41-3/4 in. - 61 x 106 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: American / Locomotive Company / Office of / Engineer of Construction
  - Railroad - Map Showing Proposed Crossing of 9th St. / For Siding With Dixie Paper Company's Plant, 56-B-3, 1917, Dimensions: 44 x 33 in. - 112 x 84 cm.; Scale: 1" = 4'; Media: Blueprint with pencil and ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - Mill Street Fence Line, 10944-B-5, 1920, Dimensions: 24 x 30 in. - 61 x 76 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: Blueprint with red pencil notions; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - Plat of a triangular Parcel of Land / on the North Side of Williamsburg Avenue / Between the C. & O. Ry. Tunnel Track Overpass / and Old King's Mill Building, 11000-B-2, 1920, Dimensions: 18-1/4 x 38-1/2 in. - 46 x 97 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: India ink and orange ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
    Drawn By: Dept. of Public Works / Richmond Va.
  - Railroad - Proposed Track Up Delaware Avenue for / Industrial Purposes - Acme Land Co., 11171-A-6, 1921, Dimensions: 36 x 60-1/4 in. - 91 x 155 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint with red pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 55)
    Drawn By: R. D. Trimble & Co. / Consulting and Constructing Engineers / Richmond, Va.
  - Railroad - New 30' Reinforced Concrete Sewer Crossing to be Constructed / by the City of Richmond, 11246-A-2, 1922, Dimensions: 8-1/4 x 20-1/2 in. - 21 x 52 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Photostat; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
  - Railroad - [Plan of C. & O. Railroad yards near Canal St. between Seventh and Ninth streets], 63-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 29-1/2 x 25-3/4 in. - 75 x 66 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - Plan / of / proposed location of Tracks in Dock Street, 11-A-1, n.d., Dimensions: 15 x 57-1/2 in. - 38 x 146 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - Pencil Line Shows St. line as / given for C & O RR abutments by EMyers Jr. / On Col. WE Cutshaw's order, 19-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 18-1/4 x 92-1/4 in. - 46 x 117 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: Pencil, India ink, red ink, and blue ink on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - C. & O. Ry. / Proposed Double - Track Elevated Railways / and / Passenger Station / Richmond, Va., 40-B-4, n.d., Dimensions: 29-3/4 x 60-1/2 in. - 76 x 193 cm.; Scale: 1" = 300'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
    Drawn By: H. Frazier / Chief Engineer
  - Railroad - Dock Street / under C. & O. Viaduct, 10583-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 21 x 36 in. - 53 x 91 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 52)
  - Railroad - [Plan of railroad yard along Fourteenth St. near James River, 28-B-4, n.d., Dimensions: 20 x 18-1/2 in. - 51 x 47 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint with red pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 53)
  - Railroad - [Plan of R. F. & P. Railroad tracks and sidings along Broad Street with list of property transfers for right-of-way], 57-C-1, n.d., Dimensions: 17-3/4 x 35 in. - 45 x 89 cm.; Scale: 1" = 200'; Media: Blueprints (damaged); Sheets: 2 (Folder 55)
  - River / Creek - [Record of freshet of 1877 in the Gillies Creek valley], 1-B-4, 1877, Dimensions: 38 x 20-1/4 in. - 96 x 51 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
  - River / Creek - Map of the Portion of Land Condemned / by the Committee on the Improvement of the James River, 7-D-4, 1887, Dimensions: 23-1/4 x 19-1/2 in. - 59 x 49 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
  - River / Creek - [Topographic study of area of proposed penstock], 5-A-2, 1894, Dimensions: 14-3/4 x 18-1/2 in. - 38 x 47 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Proposed Changes in Channel of Shockoe Creek, 19-B-4, 1896, Dimensions: 19 x 37 in. - 48 x 94 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
  - River / Creek - Freshet Record of James River / Year 1893 and following, 19-A-2, 1896, Dimensions: 13 x 21-1/4 in. - 33 x 54 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
    Drawn By: F.B. Issacs, Civ. & Hyd: Eng't.
  - River / Creek - Plan for / Deck Scow / for City of Richmond, 47-A-2, 1903, Dimensions: 14 x 32 in. - 36 x 81 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Plan Showing Property Owners on West Side / of Shockoe Creek bet. Dock & Grace Sts., 48-A-1, 1904, Dimensions: 11 x 38 in. - 28 x 96 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
    Drawn By: Office of the City Engineer
  - River / Creek - Concrete Arch for Shockoe Creek 7th. & Hospital Sts., 51-A-1, 1904, Dimensions: 9 x 10-3/4 in. - 23 x 27 cm.; Scale: 1" =4'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 67)
  - River / Creek - [Cross section and profile of Shockoe creek in area of Walnut Alley], 37-A-1c, 1906, Dimensions: 10-1/2 x 22 in. - 26 x 53 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
  - River / Creek - Plan Showing the Location of the Proposed New Channel for Shockoe Creek / from Washington St. to the Southern End of the Completed Channel near 7th and Hospital Sts., 22-C-1, 1907, Dimensions: 25-1/2 x 77 in. - 65 x 195 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
  - River / Creek - Map Showing Location of New Channel of / Shockoe Creek, 55-A-1, 1907, Dimensions: 8 x 13-3/4 in. - 20 x 35 cm.; Scale: [1" = 20']; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder 56)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office. Richmond, Va. / F.A. Harwood, Del.
  - River / Creek - Plan Showing the Location of the Proposed New Channel / for Shockoe Creek from Main to Washington St, 59-B-2, 1907, Dimensions: 18-1/2 x 62-1/2 in. - 47 x 119 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: Blueprint with red pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
    Drawn By: Office of Chief Engineer Seaboard Air Line Ry. / Portsmouth, Va
  - River / Creek - James River, Va. / Soundings Made May 5, 1911', 49-B-4, 1911, Dimensions: 20-3/4 x 37 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Blueprint with red ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
    Drawn By: G. S. Engineer Office / 28th N. 9th St. Richmond, Va.
  - River / Creek - Plan and Elevation of Concrete Invert / In Bacon's Quarter Branch at Deneen St., 55-B-3, 1912, Dimensions: 19-1/2 x 31-1/4 in. - 50 x 79 cm.; Scale: 1/2" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
    Drawn By: City Engineers Office / Richmond, VA. / M.O. Hankins Asst. Eng'r / JS Potts Jr / Del.
  - River / Creek - Shockoe Creek / Cary St to Dock St / Plan Showing Property Lines and / Occupation with proposed Right of Way / for Widening Creek, 76-C-2, 1914, Dimensions: 29-1/4 x 30-1/4 in. - 74 x 77 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
  - River / Creek - Shockoe Creek / from / Cary St. to Dock St. / Plan of adjacent property, railway tracks etc., 76-C-2a, 1915, Dimensions: 21-3/4 x 36 in. - 56 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
  - River / Creek - Map of Shockoe Creek from Dock St. to 7th & Hospital Sts. / Showing High Water Elevations at Certain Points Along the Creek Freshet of Sept. 6th 1917, 96-B-1, 1917, Dimensions: 25 x 41-3/4 in. - 64 x 106 cm.; Scale: 1 " = 100'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Map, Plans and Sections / Proposed New Location Wrought Iron Flume / Dock at Shockoe Creek / South of Dock Street, 10639-B-1, 1918, Dimensions: 36-1/2 x 24 in. - 93 x 61 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India ink, yellow ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Flood Relief Project / Lower Shockoe Creek, 11198-A-4, 1923, Dimensions: 42-1/4 x 52 in. - 107 x 132 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink and yellow ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 57)
    Drawn By: Department of Public Works / Bureau of Design
  - River / Creek - Profile Kingsland Creek / to / City Point, 29-D3, n.d., Dimensions: Various; Scale: None; Media: Pencil on paper (fragile); Sheets: 5 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - [Plan of river embankment in area of the Tredegar Works], 1-A-6, n.d., Dimensions: 11-1/4 x 38 in. - 28 x 96 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Map / Bacon Quarter Branch & Shockoe Creek / Between Oak St. & Clay St., 10574B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 17-1/2 x 37 in. - 44 x 94 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - [Plan of Shockoe Creek and elevations of street crossings from Clay St. to the James River], 2-B-4, n.d., Dimensions: 28 x 38 in. - 71 x 97 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Map of Land Needed / for / Improvement of Shockoe Creek / at 7th and Hospital Sts., 15-A-1, n.d., Dimensions: 10-1/2 x 13-1/2 in. - 26 x 34 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Details / of / Shockoe Creek Improvement, 5-B-4, n.d., Dimensions: 28-1/2 x 30-1/2 in. - 72 x 77 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - [Map and profile of Shockoe Creek with sections of conduit], 9-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 15-1/4 x 41-3/4 in. - 39 x 106 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Map / of / Dock Crossing Shockoe Creek., 3-B-4, n.d., Dimensions: 30-1/2 x 28-1/4 in. - 77 x 72 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: India ink and blue ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - Shockoe Creek / from / Broad to Franklin Sts., 13-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 35-1/2 x 17 in. - 90 x 43 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India inks, and colored inks on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 56)
  - River / Creek - [Plan and profile of James River from Richmond to Old Point Comfort], 4-D-4, n.d., Dimensions: 33-1/4 x 37-1/2 in. - 84 x 95 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 5 (Folder 57)